

BRIAN JIMÉNEZ MOEDANO

CONTACT

07440, Mexico City Mexico Mobile: 5569121984 brianjmoedano@gmail.com

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, **PROFILES**

· https://brianjm21.github.io/

EDUCATION

January 2023 No Degree: IOS Development OGUM, Mexico City, Mexico

December 2022 No Degree: IOS Development Codecademy, Online

December 2013 Bachelor of Science: Electrical. **Electronics Engineering** Technologies

Universidad Nacional Autónoma De México, Mexico City, Mexico

LANGUAGES

Spanish

Bilingual or Proficient (C2)

Upper intermediate (B2)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With a bachelor degree in Electronic Engineer, I've been working as a Software Developer since 2014.

During my professional career, I've had the chance to work with several tools and frameworks, as well as being part of interdisciplinary teams, colleagues and business related personalities.

With proficiency in object oriented design using SOLID principles, I actually have an advance specialization in iOS app development using Swift programming language.

SKILLS

- Xcode IDE usgin Swift programming language
- Unit testing using XCTest
- · API integration using URLSession, async/await and callback handlers.
- · Teamwork and Collaboration using Agile methodologies.
- · Firebase and Realm.
- CoreData
- · MVC, MVVM, VIPER

WORK HISTORY

July 2023 - Current

IOS Developer, Accenture, Mexico City, Mexico

- · Use of Xcode IDE, native iOS' APIs and swift programming language for App development.
- · Designing and implementing UI/UX with UIKit framework.
- · Integration of third party API's using Xcode's package manager and
- · Use of native URLSession framework and async/await design pattern.
- · Use of MVVM software arquitecture design.
- · Implementation of SSL certificates to safeguard API communication.
- Use of Keychain and best practices for local storage sensitive user data.
- · Team collaboration, planning and working using AGILE methodologies.
- · Version control usgin GIT, GITHUB and GITLAB.

July 2022 - July 2023

IOS Developer, Freelancer, Mexico City, Mexico

- App Development for professional and personal purpose.
- Use of XCode IDE for native iOS app development, using Swift.
- UlKit and SwiftUI.
- · Integration of CoreData, FileManager y UserDefaults for local data
- · Use of third party BAAS' Realm/MongoDB and FireBase.
- Integration of native Combine and Notification Center framework, as well as Delegate Pattern for code communication.
- · API integration using URLSession framework, and callback handlers.
- · Use of MVC, MVVM and VIPER arquitecture design.
- · S.O.L.I.D. principles.

October 2015 - July 2022

Software Engineer, ISSFAM, Mexico City, Mexico

- Designed and developed software solutions using PRO-IV IDE, with native object oriented programming language.
- Update and maintain of institutional data bases.
- Ensure best practices and safety measures for data privacy and protection.
- Refactored legacy codebase for improved maintainability, paving the way for easier future updates.
- Worked with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability, and performance.

July 2014 - October 2015

Software Engineer Intern, *Instituto Nacional De Psiquiatría*, Mexico City, Mexico

- Software development using National Instruments LabVIEW IDE for controlling a fluorescent microscope for digital image acquisition.
- Supporting role in other technical activities in the neurophysiology laboratory.

January 2014 - July 2014

Software Engineer Intern, Flopac, Mexico City, Mexico

- · Software development using National Instruments' LabVIEW IDE.
- Supporting role in virtual instrumentation development, for industrial and academic purposes.